remax.ca 2018-01-21

# Privacy Policy - Guide You Home

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Effective April 13, 2016

This is the Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) for REMAX.ca which is run through the combined efforts of  RE/MAX of Western Canada, providing information on properties in the provinces and territories of British Columbia, Alberta, Saskatchewan, Manitoba, Yukon, Northwest and Nunavut (“RWC”) and RE/MAX Integra, providing information on properties in the provinces of Ontario, Newfoundland, New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and Prince Edward Island  (“Integra”) (collectively “RG”, “us,” “our,” or “we”).  Your privacy is very important to us. The purpose of this Policy is to disclose what Personal Information (as defined below) and other information we may collect from you, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, as well as the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure of that information to other parties.  
We may collect information through our website located at REMAX.ca, other sites accessible via subdomains, mobile versions of any of these sites, and any other site on which this Policy is posted (each a “Site” and, collectively, the “Sites”), as well as our mobile application (the “Application”).  The Application and Sites are collectively referred to as the “Services”).  Terms not otherwise defined here will have the same definitions as set forth in our Terms of Service.

Except as otherwise discussed in this Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you through our Services. For some services, we may collect and transfer Personal Information to a service provider, or you may visit other sites or service providers through third-party links in our Services, who may collect and use your Personal Information for other purposes. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these third-party sites before you disclose your Personal Information to others.  
If you do not agree to the terms of this Policy, please do not use the Services.

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

We may collect personal and other information about you when you use our Services, as described below. “Personal Information” is information which can be used to distinguish or trace an individual’s identity, such as their name, mailing address, email address, or phone number, whether used alone, or when combined with other personal or identifying information which is linked or linkable to a specific individual.  
We typically collect Personal Information and other data from you, and use that information as set forth in this Policy or otherwise communicated to you from time to time (subject to your consent when required by applicable laws).

**WHEN YOU REGISTER OR SIGN UP FOR OUR SERVICES**

You may register on our Services in order to save searches, sign up for alerts, access our real estate resources, and for other features we may add from time to time. You may be registered for our Services automatically when you contact one of our agents regarding a property or inquire about us or our Services. If you register on our Services, we collect Personal Information such as your name, email, address and any other Personal Information required on the registration form. If you wish, you may provide us your phone number. We primarily use this information to provide information you have requested, manage and correspond with you about your account, send you information and newsletters related to properties, real estate markets, information related to real estate, and/or other information we think may interest you, and for other matters described in this Policy.

**NEWSLETTERS, INQUIRIES AND EMAILS**

We may offer newsletters and/or other communications to share information with you about RE/MAX, independently owned and operated RE/MAX franchisees, independent real estate sales associates, real estate, helpful guides and information, and other topics or offers in which we believe you may be interested, about us and our related entities, or about our advertisers, sponsors, or other business partners.  You may sign up to receive information from a specific agent, office, or our general mailing list. If you inquire regarding a property, an independent RE/MAX real estate sales associate may contact you regarding that or related properties to the extent related to your inquiry.   In addition, if you indicate that a property is one of your “favourites,” you will automatically be placed on a list to receive email updates regarding that property (which will be sent by the independent listing agent).

Please note, if you choose to provide your email address or other contact information to an independent RE/MAX sales associate, we collect this information on behalf of that agent and we will submit your information to that agent.  However, we cannot control how these independent sales associates or the independently owned and operated RE/MAX offices use that information, and therefore this Policy does not apply their use of your Personal Information. Please contact the agent or office directly or follow the links included in the communications you receive from the agent to learn more about their privacy practices.

**RE/MAX TEXT MESSAGE (SMS) SERVICE – MOBILE TERMS AND CONDITIONS**

RE/MAX Text Message (SMS) Service allows you to receive text messages (SMS) on your mobile device regarding our agents’ and brokers’ properties. If you provide your phone number to us and register for SMS alerts/messaging, you consent to our collection and use of your phone number to send you updates, alerts and for other purposes listed at the time you sign up. We will not sell your phone number (although we will share it with the listing agent for the properties about which you have inquired)  or use it except for the purposes you allow. You can opt-in to this service by texting the applicable listing keyword to the designated number.  
• If you want to unsubscribe from ALL of your previously requested notifications, you can do so, at any time, simplyby texting *   STOP, END, QUIT, CANCEL, ARRET or UNSUBSCRIBE to RE/MAX at short code 28888. You will receive the following message on your mobile device: RE/MAX Mobile Services – Your subscription has been cancelled”  
• If you need further assistance,help or would like more information, text *   HELP or INFO to RE/MAX atshort code 28888.  You will receive the following messages on your mobile device:  
HELP: “RE/MAX info on demand: Not a subscription service. Text Keyword to receive listing info. Txt STOP to end. Msg/data rates may apply”  
INFO: “RE/MAX legal disclaimer. http://goo.gl/HTvP4c, webadmin@remax-oa.com, 855-307-3629 Txt STOP to end. Msg/data rates may apply”  
AIDE: “RE/MAX mentions légales. http://goo.gl/HTvP4c, 855-307-3629 txt STOP pour arreter. Fais de msg/data peuvent s’applique”  
ARRET: “Vous êtes désaboné de tout les notification RE/MAX. Pour plus de détails http://goo.gl/HTvP4c, Fais de msg/data peuvent s’applique ”  
STOP: “RE/MAX info on demand: Not a subscription service. You will not receive any more messages  .  ”

**MOBILE APPLICATION**

If you download our Application, it may request access to certain features or information on your mobile device (as disclosed during the download process ) .  We may use this information to facilitate the functionality of our Application, to better tailor our content to visitors’ needs, and to help us and certain third parties to better understand our audience.  If you have registered on our Services, it may be possible for us to combine data we collect through our Application with other information we hold about you, so that we can personalize or improve the relevance and quality of services we provide to you.

**CONTESTS OR SWEEPSTAKES**

We may operate or promote contests and sweepstakes through our Services, which may require registration in order to enter. We may collect information such as your name, phone number, address, email and other information included on the sign up form. Please note, the privacy practices of a particular contest or sweepstakes may vary from the practices stated in this Policy; for example when the contest or sweepstakes is sponsored by a third party and hosted on their site. Where the terms of a sweepstakes or contest include privacy practices that differ from or conflict with this Policy, the privacy practices of the contest or sweepstakes you entered will control, and will be disclosed in the rules for that promotion. Without limiting the foregoing, your Personal Information may be used by us or a third party to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other promotional purposes. Your entry in the contest or sweepstakes may also result in your being added to our mailing/texting lists as well as those of our promotional partners associated with the contest or sweepstakes. Acceptance of a prize may require you (unless prohibited by law) to allow us to post publicly some of your information on the Services, such as on a winner’s page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes.  
In some instances, a third-party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes on our Services (or promoted through our Services), and may collect your information. In those cases, where we are not the sponsor, operator or host of the contest or sweepstakes, we may have no control over the information collected and accordingly urge you to review the official rules of the contest/sweepstakes as well as the advertiser’s or sponsor’s privacy policy applicable to the contest or sweepstakes before participating.

**COOKIES, WEB BEACONS AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**

Our Services use cookies, which are small, commonly-used files that are transferred to your computer by us or a third party when you allow your browser to accept cookies. Similarly, we, our third party service providers or advertisers may also use “web beacons,” “pixel tags” or other tracking technologies, which are typically small pieces of code placed on a web page to monitor behavior and collect certain data regarding the actions of our guests online. These cookies and other technologies may be used to track your online traffic patterns, to enhance your experience when using our Services, to store information during your session, to personalize the Services for you based on your preferences and selections, to target advertising or content to you (as described further below) and to collect Information about you and your visit to our Services for other marketing and business purposes. You can adjust your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. However, disabling cookies may impair your user experience and disable certain features of our Services.

Our Services may use cookies or other technologies provided by website analytics services such as Google Analytics to help us better understand how our Services are used. By tracking how and when you use our Services, these technologies help us determine which features and content on our Services are most important to our visitors. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, you can turn off cookies using your browser’s settings menu; however, this may eliminate our ability to provide a personalized or user-friendly experience. To learn more about, or to opt-out of Google’s analytic and marketing services, visit Google Analytics Terms of Use, the Google Privacy Policy, or Google Analytics Opt-out.  
Data about your activities online may be collected for use in providing advertising tailored to your individual interests, either by us, our affiliates, or third parties. We may use third parties such as network advertisers and ad exchanges to serve advertisements across the internet and may use third party analytics service providers to evaluate and provide us and/or third parties with information about the use of these ads on third party websites and viewing of ads and of our content. The information collected may include information about your visits to our Services, such as the pages you have viewed. These third-party tracking technologies may be set to, among other things: (a) help deliver advertisements to you that you might be interested in; (b) prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times; and (c) understand the effectiveness of the advertisements that have been delivered to you. This collection and ad targeting takes place both on our Services and on third-party websites or services that participate in the ad network, such as websites that feature advertisements delivered by the ad network. This process also helps us track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. We and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as a DoubleClick cookie) together to report how your ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to our Services. To learn more about how to opt out of Google’s use of cookies, visit the Google’s Ads Settings, here. To learn more about how to opt out of DoubleClick’s use of cookies, visit the DoubleClick opt-out page, here.

Please note, our Services do not currently respond to browser do-not-track signals. Further, our third party advertising networks may install their own cookies, including cookies that may track our visitors to our Services over time and across third party sites, and which may change over time without notice to you or RG.  If you wish to take steps to opt-out of tracking by certain online advertisers, you can visit the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page, here, or the Network Advertising Initiative, here.

**LOCATION; IP ADDRESSES; AND CLICK-STREAM DATA**

Our Services and servers may collect other Information from you. The Information collected cannot typically be used to identify you personally. However, if you have registered on the Services, it may be possible for us to link certain information to information that identifies you personally. Information collected through our Services includes: information sent to us automatically by your web browser, the address of the web page you were visiting when you accessed our Services, information about your operating system, the browser you are using; the date and time of your visit; and online traffic patterns and content accessed throughout our Services. If you allow the use of location services, we may also collect location information through our Services. This information allows us to better tailor our content to visitors’ needs, to localize and personalize content, and helps us and certain third parties to better understand our audience.

**IF YOU CONTACT US THROUGH THE SERVICES.**

You may contact us with questions about our Services, real estate, our business or other matters.  Any information you provide through our Services will be used in the context of resolving your request or answering your inquiry, or to provide additional information related to that inquiry. We may also place you on our marketing list for information related to your inquiry or which we otherwise believe would be of interest to you, and we may otherwise use your information as described in this Policy.

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION**

We use collected information to make available and to improve our high standard of reliable services. We use such information to:

•    respond to inquiries or service requests and monitor such responses;  
•    provide information about and market our products or services or those of the R.G.RE/MAX franchise network of independently owned offices and their affiliated independent real estate agents;  
•    resolve problems;  
•    manage the Services and assess usage;  
•     enhance or personalize your experience using our Services;  
•     inform you of offers or new features that we believe may be of interest to you;  
•    provide information or services you have requested;  
•    process or maintain your subscription to a newsletter or mailing list;  
•    facilitate various programs, promotions or contests in which you participate;  
•    target advertising or content, or for other advertising, promotional or marketing purposes;  
•    study the use and popularity of various areas of our Services and to improve our Services; and  
•    analyze general locations where our content is viewed (by reviewing IP addresses). We may also use such information for other purposes related to our business or that of our related entities, as well as for any other purpose described in this Policy or any other agreement you may enter with RG, RWC, or Integra, or otherwise as we may disclose to you or to which you consent from time to time.

**HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION**

Information we collect may be shared with a variety of parties, depending upon the purpose for and context in which that information was provided. When you search for a property, we will redirect you to the site of an independently owned and operated RE/MAX franchise office and provide information you have submitted to us, including the parameters of the search, and if you have registered, we may provide your contact information to that office. Similarly, if you request to be contacted by an agent or office or otherwise request information from us, we will disclose the Personal Information you provide to appropriate affiliates of RG to satisfy your request.

We reserve the right to share your Personal Information with our current or future affiliated entities, subsidiaries, and parent companies. We may also share your Personal Information and other information with trusted third parties for marketing, advertising, or other commercial purposes, and we may occasionally share your Personal Information with trusted parties who may have information that we believe will interest you.  
We sometimes offer promotions, such as sweepstakes or contests, in conjunction with a sponsor, and may share your information with these sponsors.  We may also occasionally share Personal Information with our affiliated entities or third parties who have offers or information we believe would be of interest to you. For example, we may share certain information with certain third parties including marketing partners, national industry organizations, and prospective affiliates. We may provide such information as part of Google’s DoubleClick program.

We may share analyses of our server logs, including details regarding usage of our Services and general information about our audience, with current or potential advertisers or business partners. Such disclosures typically aggregate usage data from these analyses and other information not generally considered to be Personal Information.

We may, without your consent, share Personal Information and other data with service providers who provide certain services on our behalf, or in the other circumstances noted below. For example, we may share certain Personal Information we collect with third parties such as providers of data hosting or processing services, payment processors, or other service providers. We also reserve the right to share any information we possess or data derived from it with service providers or others if such information has been reasonably de-identified.

In addition, in the event that we go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition, liquidation or sale of all or a portion of our assets, Personal Information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred, or may be disclosed (subject to confidentiality restrictions) during the due diligence process. If such a transfer occurs, the acquiring company’s use of your Personal Information will still be subject to this Policy, and any privacy choices you selected in your online profile on our Services.

Finally, we may, without your consent, access and disclose your Personal Information, any communications sent or received by you, and any other information that we may have about you as may be permitted or as we believe in good faith may be reasonably necessary to comply with any law, regulation, rule or court order; pursuant to subpoenas or other requests from governmental, regulatory or administrative agencies or law enforcement authorities; to respond to any claims, or to prevent, investigate, identify persons or organizations potentially involved in, or take any action regarding suspected fraud, violations of our Terms of Service, or activity that appears to us to be illegal or we believe may expose us to legal liability. Additionally, we may disclose Personal Information in situations that we believe to be emergencies involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or property, if we believe that your information in any way relates to that threat.

**YOUR CHOICES**

It is possible for you to use most of our Services without giving us any Personal Information. When you do register with us or give us Personal Information, you may sometimes have an opportunity at the time we collect your information to limit e-mail communications from us or opt-out of receiving emails from third parties, or you can unsubscribe from email newsletters or similar communications by clicking on the unsubscribe link in every email.  You may opt out of all information sharing with third parties for marketing purposes by contacting us at the address or email below.  
As discussed above, to opt out of DoubleClick’s use of cookies, visit the DoubleClick opt-out page here, and if you wish to take steps to opt-out of tracking by certain online advertisers, you can visit the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out page here, or the Network Advertising Initiative here. You may opt-out of information sharing with third parties for marketing purposes by emailing us at optout@remax.ca

**HOW CAN I ACCESS OR UPDATE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

You may access or update any Personal Information by logging into your account and updating your profile. If you need more information, you may contact us using our ‘Contact Us  ’ form. We will respond to reasonable requests for access or revision and will provide access to the extent required or allowed by law. However, we may decide not to grant access or make revisions where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the individual’s privacy in any given case, or when the rights of others would be violated by granting the access.

**LINKS AND REDIRECTION TO THIRD PARTY SERVICES**

The Services contain links and may redirect you to Third Party Services (as defined in our Terms of Service)).   Third Party Services are not under the control of RG, and RG is not responsible for the data privacy or security practices of such Third Party Services, or how they may use the information you provide.  Please be aware that when you enter a Third Party Service, any information you provide, including financial information, is subject to the terms of use and privacy policy of that site or service.

**INFORMATION SECURITY**

We have implemented reasonable security measures to safeguard the Personal Information you provide us. However, please keep in mind that we cannot be liable for the actions of third parties to whom we may transfer your Personal Information in accordance with this Policy. Furthermore, please remember that “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet, and accordingly we cannot provide any guarantee that your Personal Information or any other information you provide us will remain secure.

**EFFECTIVE DATE; POLICY CHANGES**

Each time you use the Services, the current version of the Policy will apply. Accordingly, when you use the Services, you should check the date of this Policy (which appears at the top of the Policy) and review any changes since the last version. We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time and without notice other than simply posting such modifications. Any such modifications will be effective immediately upon posting on the Services.

**LIMITATION OF LIABILITY**

By providing us with any Personal Information, you expressly and unconditionally release and hold harmless RG, RWC, Integra, and each of their related entities, parents, service providers, licensors, and its or their respective officers, directors, employees or agents (collectively the “RG Parties”) from any and all liability for any injuries, loss or damage of any kind arising from or in connection with the use and/or misuse of your collected Personal Information. In addition, while we take reasonable steps to prevent third party companies from making unauthorized use of your Personal Information, we cannot be held be held liable for any injuries, loss or damage of any kind arising from or in connection with the use and/or misuse of your collected Personal Information by those third parties.

UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES SHALL ANY RG PARTIES BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO DIRECT, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL, LOST PROFITS OR LOST REVENUE) THAT RESULT FROM THE USE OF THE INFORMATION OR MATERIALS ON THIS SITE, EVEN IF THE RG PARTIES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.  INTERNATIONAL GUESTS.

If you are accessing our Services from outside of Canada or the U.S.A., you consent to the transfer of your information to both Canada and the U.S.A., and the processing, use, and sharing of your information in accordance with this Policy. In addition, if you access links to the global RE/MAX website in order to search for properties in other countries, your information may be transferred to or processed in other countries and you consent to such transfer and processing.  Regardless of where your information is collected or transferred, the information will be treated in accordance with this Policy.

**CONTACT US**

You may contact us with your questions or comments regarding this Policy or our information collection and dissemination practices at:

For matters related to the provinces and territories of British Columbia, Alberta, Saskatchewan, Manitoba, Yukon, Northwest and NanavutNunavut, please contact:

RE/MAX of Western Canada  
#340-1060 Manhattan Drive  
Kelowna, BC V1Y 9X9  
Email:  webmaster@remax.ca

For matters related to the provinces of Ontario, Newfoundland, New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and Prince Edward Island, please contact:

RE/MAX Integra  
7101 Syntex Drive,  
Mississauga, ON L5N 6H4 ON, Canada  
Email: webadmin@remax-oa.com
